

Antonia Frey

About Me

Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience. Since the beginning of my career, I have contributed to diverse projects across industries like telecommunications, automotive, and energy, building applications from scratch, implementing new features, and finding solutions. Beyond my technical skills, I am flexible, communicative, and motivated to expand my knowledge, master new concepts and share knowledge. If there are any tools or technologies that I am not yet familiar with, I am committed to learn them.

Contact

- +4915146782868
- in Antonia Alice Frey
- thebughuntress
- antoniaalicefrey.com

Personal Information

Citizenship: Swiss, German

Located in: Freiburg (Germany)

Les Houches (France)

Languages:

- German (native language, C2)
- English (C1)
- Spanish (C1)
- French (B1)

Technologies & Tools

- Programming Languages
 Python, TypeScript, JS, Java, C#
- Frontend
 React, Vue, Angular, Redux, Material UI,
 Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, HTML/CSS
- Backend
 Python Django, NodeJS, MongoDB,
 SQL
- Testing
 Java/Selenium, Cypress / Cucumber,
 Postman (API Testing), Jest
- Agile Practices Git, CI/CD, SCRUM, Jira, Confluence

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · IT CONSULTANT

Devoteam GmbH, Frankfurt, Germany · Remote

February 2022 – Now

- Development of web applications, leveraging cloud technologies, for data visualization with React, MaterialUI, with TypeScript or JavaScript, increasing user satisfaction through the implementation of new functionality.
- Transforming client requirements into technical solutions, collaborated in meetings to ensure alignment with stakeholder expectations
- Resolving bugs, validating urgent fixes, developing automated tests with Java/Selenium, Cypress, leading to a reduction in system downtime
- Implemented Git integration within GitLab CI/CD pipelines to optimize version control and automate deployment workflows.
- Contributed to an agile SCRUM environment using Git, Jira, and Confluence to manage tasks and document workflows.

SYSTEM ANALYST

ELCA Informatique SA, Granada, Spain · Switzerland Jan. 2021 – Jan. 2022

- Automation of business-critical processes and implementation of new functionality in the company-wide production ERP system with Python.
- Creating and optimizing VBA scripts to generate business reports.
- $\diamond\,$ Querying databases with SQL to ensure data accuracy and integrity.
- Conducted business analysis for new features, drafting user stories and acceptance criteria, and coordinating client meetings with stakeholders in Switzerland while collaborating within an international team comprising Spanish, German, and French-speaking colleagues.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (INTERNSHIP)

Intel Labs, Karlsruhe, Germany

Aug. 2019 - Jan. 2020

- Automotive software development for an open-source simulator CARLA.org used for autonomous driving research.
- Developed traffic scenarios which describe traffic situations and vehicle behaviors like a lane change with Python.
- ♦ Debugging, testing, and implementing unsupported Parser features.

SYSTEM ENGINEER (INTERNSHIP)

BMW M, Munich, Germany

Sep. 2018 - Feb. 2019

- Developing a Windows desktop app with C# to automatically translate bus communication protocols from LIN to CAN and vice versa.
- Antenna measurements during test drives in disguised prototype cars.
- Coordination of the annual tire change for vehicle fleets, including vehicle bookings, mechanic scheduling, and measurement/technical documentation of wheelbase parameters.

Education

M. SC. ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING AND INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT)

2018 - 2020

B. SC. ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING AND INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) 2013 – 2018

Certificates

- ♦ 2024 Professional Python Programmer Level 1, pythoninstitute.org
- ♦ 2024 ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level, atsqa.org
- ♦ 2023 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon
- ♦ 2023 Google Cloud Engineer, Google
- ♦ 2023 Google Cloud Digital Leader, Google
- ♦ 2022 Professional Scrum Master I, scrum.org